Staff Room
（魅音(みおん)）教室のほうは
クーラーがないんで―
Staff Room
Since there isn't air
conditioning in the classroom...
...we can't close the window.
窓を
閉めるわけには いかないんです
The principal is contacting
the forest agency right now...
（知恵(ちえ)）今 校長先生が―
営林署のほうに
連絡を取っていますので
もう少し我慢してください
...so please be patient.
I think it's the smell of the
chemicals they're going to use...
（知恵）多分 作業に使う薬の
においだと思いますけど
なんとかしてもらいますから
（魅音）分かりました
...so we'll have it taken care of.
Okay.
（知恵）はい もしもし
雛見沢(ひなみざわ)分校でございます
Hello, this is Hinamizawa School.
Ryugu-san?
Where are you right now?
（知恵）竜宮(りゅうぐう)さん？
今どこにいるんですか？
分かりました
今から すぐ行きます
Okay.
I'll be right there.
（圭一(けいいち)）ええっ？ レナから電話？
（魅音）うん
Rena called?
Yeah, Chie-sensei went
where Rena wanted to meet.
知恵先生が指定された場所に
会いに行ったみたい
Everyone, stand up, stand up!
（ﾚﾅ）みんな 起立 起立！
Gather at the center
of the classroom.
（ﾚﾅ）教室の真ん中に集まって！
（圭一）レナ！
- Rena!
- Can't you hear me?
（ﾚﾅ）聞こえない？
魅ぃちゃん 委員長でしょう
みんなに指示して
Mi-chan, you're class
president, right? Order them.
Rena, what are you do...
（魅音）レナ あんた 何やって…
- "Atonement" Chapter -
Episode 05: RETAKE
When They Cry
Furimuita sono ushiro no
(shoumen dare)?
Kurayami ni tsume wo tatete
(yoru wo hikisaita).
Amadare wa chi no shizuku to
natte nodo wo tsutai ochiru.
Mou dokonimo kaeru
basho ga nai nara...
...kono yubi tomare
watashi no yubi ni.
Sono yubi goto tsuretette ageru.
Higurashi ga naku
akazu no mori e.
Atomodori wa mou dekinai.
（無線）本日 午後１時ごろ―
At roughly 1 PM today
at Hinamizawa School...
雛見沢営林署内の雛見沢分校にて
教室籠城事件発生
...within the forest agency, a
classroom is being held hostage.
All officers,
head to the forest agency...
全車は至急 雛見沢営林署へ…
It's unknown whether there's
a suspect besides Rena Ryugu.
（熊谷(くまがい)）竜宮礼奈(れいな)以外に
犯人がいるかは不明です
（熊谷）
カーテンが閉められているので―
Since the curtains are closed,
we can't confirm the situation.
状況も一切 確認できていません
What about the forest agency?
（大石(おおいし)）営林署のほうは？
The staff wasn't present,
so it's only the 15 students.
（熊谷）職員は不在でした
よって 生徒15名のみ
（小宮山(こみやま)）大石さん
（大石）うん？
Oishi-san!
（小宮山）車載電話に犯人からです
（大石）ンンッ…
We have a call from the suspect.
Hello? This is Oishi.
もしもし 大石です
Is this Oishi-san?
（ﾚﾅ）
大石さんですか？ どうも 竜宮です
Hello. This is Ryugu.
Well, well.
（大石）どうもどうも！
（ﾚﾅ）
大石さんは私の味方ですよね？
You're on my side, aren't you?
Of course.
当然です
Let's reveal the Sonozaki's
conspiracy together.
あなたと私で 園崎(そのざき)家の
陰謀を暴こうじゃないですか
圭一君も 一時期は―
At first, Keiichi-kun
also didn't believe me.
私が言ってることを
信じてくれなかったんです
（ﾚﾅ）でも 今は もう私の味方です
But now he's on my side.
Right?
Yeah.
I see.
（大石）分かりました
ならば 圭一君にも―
Then I want to say
hi to our new ally.
新しい仲間として
ご挨拶がしたいです
出てもらうことは できますか？
Can he talk on the phone?
（ﾚﾅ）いいよ　圭一君
（大石）あっ…
Sure.
Keiichi-kun.
（ﾚﾅ）大石さんから
It's from Oishi-san.
Hello. This is Maebara.
もしもし 前原(まえばら)です
Well, well. This is
Oishi with the Okinomiya police.
どうも 興宮(おきのみや)署の大石です
（圭一）はい
Yeah.
What is Ryugu-san
doing right now?
竜宮さんは今 何をしていますか？
（圭一）人質の みんなの所に…
She's with the hostages.
前原さん イエスなら“はい”
Maebara-san,
if it's yes, say yes...
...if no, nod by saying yeah.
ノーなら“ええ”と
相づちを打ってください
あなたは 竜宮さんが
何を要求しようとしているか―
Do you know what
Ryugu-san wants?
知っていますか？
（圭一）ええ
Yeah.
あなたは
竜宮さんに脅迫されて―
You're pretending to be on her side
because you were threatened?
従っているフリをしている
（圭一）はい
Yes.
犯人は竜宮さん１人だけ？
（圭一）はい
Is Ryugu-san the only suspect?
Yes.
See?
Keiichi is on our side, right?
（ﾚﾅ）
ねっ？ 圭一君は味方でしょう？
Yes, yes...
Now it's your turn to talk.
…で 今度は
大石さんが話してくれる番
前の電話で約束した―
As promised
in our last phone call...
園崎家関係の捜査は
どうなってますか？
...how is the investigation
of the Sonozaki family going?
寄生虫の研究施設は
発見できましたか？
Were you able to find
the research lab of the parasites?
あ～ 今ですね
県警の暴対と公安部で―
The crime investigation unit
and public security department...
...are preparing
a mass investigation.
一斉捜査の準備中なんです
何しろ…
（ﾚﾅ）遅すぎる！
- It's quite...
- You're too slow!
How dare you be so slow?
何をのんびりとしたことを！
（ﾚﾅ）大石さん
本当に私の味方なんですよね？
Oishi-san, you really are
on my side, aren't you?
答えてください
（大石）もちろんですとも
Answer me.
Of course.
It's just that, um...
ただですね その…
Without evidence,
we can't take action easily.
証拠がないと
簡単には動けないんですよ
（ﾚﾅ）証拠？
Evidence?
はい
（ﾚﾅ）分かりました
Yes.
I understand.
三四(みよ)さんのスクラップ帳を
お渡しします
I'll give you
Miyo-san's scrapbooks.
それで ほかの警察の人たちを
一刻も早く説得してください
So hurry and convince
the other police departments.
ああ 助かります
That would be helpful.
I'll come and pick them up.
では
私が受け取りにまいりましょう
いえ 圭一君に持っていかせます
No. I'll let Keiichi-kun take them.
（大石）興宮署の大石です
I'm Oishi of the Okinomiya police.
（圭一）
すみません レナから… その…
I'm sorry.
Rena told me not
to say unrelated things.
“余計なおしゃべりは するな”と
言われてます
分かりました
I understand.
（大石）大丈夫です
竜宮さんからは見えていません
It's fine.
Ryugu-san can't see here.
（圭一）これは？
This is...
（大石）
教室へ戻る途中で読んでください
Read it on your way
back to the classroom.
Connect the earphone to
the wiretapping device to talk.
“盗聴器はイヤホンを着ければ
会話も可能”
“護身用スプレーの
射程は１メートル”
The self-defense spray
reaches up to one meter.
“顔面を狙うこと”
Aim for the face.
What are you doing, Rena?
（圭一）何やってんだよ レナ！
I'm spreading gasoline.
（ﾚﾅ）ガソリンまいてるんだよ
（圭一）本気かよ？
Are you serious?
万が一のときの保険なの
It's insurance
in case of an emergency.
（圭一）でも ガソリンって お前…
But gasoline? Are you...
Gasoline?
ガソリン！
If the vaporized gasoline ignites,
it'd be a huge explosion!
気化したガソリンに引火したら
大爆発
学校ごと 吹き飛んじまいます！
It would blow up the entire school!
（警官）失礼します
Excuse me!
In the scrapbook we got earlier...
（警官）先ほど
受け取ったスクラップ帳の中に―
犯人からと思われる手紙が
見つかりました
...there was a letter that
seems to be from the suspect.
なに？
What?
I will probably claw at
my throat and die tonight.
（ﾚﾅ）私は多分 今夜中に
首をかきむしって死ぬでしょう
So I'm setting 7:00 PM
as the time limit for negotiation.
ですので 今夜の19時を
交渉の期限とさせていただきます
If the mass investigation
doesn't take place by 7:00...
19時までに
一斉捜査が行われなかった場合―
人質全員と一緒に ガソリンで
焼け死ぬことを選びたいと思います
...then I shall choose to burn
to death with the hostages.
7:00 PM...
19時…
（熊谷）今 18時前です
It's before 6:00 now.
あと１時間か…
We have an hour left.
I have also prepared another
way to set off the explosion.
（ﾚﾅ）なお 別の手段で
爆発させる方法も用意してあります
それは
ガソリンとキッチンタイマーを―
It's like a simple time bomb made
from gas and a kitchen timer.
組み合わせた 簡単な
時限爆弾のような物です
キッチンタイマー…
A kitchen timer.
（ﾚﾅ）もちろん それも
19時を設定させていただきました
I have also set that for 7:00.
どうか 速やかに
行動を開始されますよう―
I hope you take action quickly.
よろしくお願いいたします
To my ally, Oishi-san.
私の味方の大石さんへ
竜宮レナ
Rena Ryugu.
Damn it!
（大石）くそったれ！
なにが味方だ！
How dare you call me an ally?
Stop! Rena!
（圭一）やめろ レナ！
You promised you
wouldn't move from that wall.
（ﾚﾅ）圭一君は
そこの壁から動かない約束だよ！
（ﾚﾅ）私が許せないのは
魅ぃちゃんが死体を掘り出して―
I can't forgive the fact you dug up
the corpses and betrayed me!
私を警察に売ったことだよ！
I trusted you!
信じてたのに！ 信じてたのに！
（殴る音）
I trusted you!
Stop, Rena! Stop!
やめろ レナ！ やめてくれー！
Don't come any closer!
近寄るな！
それ以上 近づけば
ライターを点火するよ
If you come any closer,
I'll light the lighter.
Hello.
あっ 大石さん 何ですか？
Oishi-san?
What do you want?
（ﾚﾅ）はい… はい
Yes.
Can you hear me?
（熊谷）聞こえますか？
興宮署の熊谷と申します
This is Kumagai
with the Okinomiya police.
聞こえているなら
せきばらいをしてください
If you can hear me, please cough.
Great.
ああ 良かった
今から言うことを
よく聞いてください
Please listen carefully
to what I'm going to say.
犯人は 時限発火装置を
仕掛けていると予告しています
The suspect said she set
a timed explosive device.
キッチンタイマーを
流用した単純な物でしょうが
It's a simple kind made
with a kitchen timer, but...
今の教室は それで十分 爆発します
It can blow up the classroom.
予告では
タイマーの設定は午後７時
According to the warning,
the timer is set for 7:00 PM.
あと15分です
It's in 15 minutes.
15分？ あっ…
15 minutes?
（ﾚﾅ）時間どおりです
Right on time.
What can I do?
（圭一）どうしろと？
（熊谷）あなたに
時限発火装置を見つけだして―
We want you to find the timed
explosive device and turn it off.
解除していただきたいのです
（圭一）俺に？
Me?
タイマーは コンセントに差して
動くタイプでしょうが
I believe the timer is set
by plugging it into an outlet.
Is there something plugged
into an outlet in the classroom?
教室内のコンセントに
何か差さっていませんか？
（圭一）いえ
No.
Or it might be set
in another room.
あるいは ほかの部屋に
仕掛けられている可能性があります
全部 調べろってことかよ？
あと15分で…
You want me
to search all the rooms?
In 15 minutes?
（梨花(りか)）圭一
（圭一）あっ…
Keiichi.
梨花ちゃん
Rika-chan?
You heard?
（圭一）聞こえたのか？
（梨花）うん
Traps are my specialty.
（沙都子(さとこ)）
トラップは私の専売特許でしてよ
I won't let Rena-san
steal my expertise.
レナさんに お株を奪われるなんて
死んでも死にきれませんわ
Then I'm gonna ask our
club's greatest trap expert.
それじゃ
我が部最高のトラップ名人に聞くぜ
To blow up this room...
この部屋を爆破するには
どこに時限発火装置を仕掛ける？
...where would you put
the timed explosive device?
I guess I have to do it.
しかたありませんわね
I'll show Rena-san that her trap
is nonsense when I'm serious.
（沙都子）本気の私の前には
レナさんのトラップなんて―
問題にならないということを
証明してさし上げましてよ
When They Cry
（ﾚﾅ）
それじゃ 全然 間に合いません！
Then that wouldn't be in time!
Do you really
understand what I'm saying?
大石さんは 本当に私の言うことを
理解してくださってるんですか？
I think there's a cord somewhere.
（沙都子）多分 どこかに
コードがあるはずなんですけど
それを確認できれば…
（圭一）よし 任せろ
If I could find that, then...
Okay. Leave it to me.
What?
What happened, Keiichi-kun?
なに？ どうしたの？ 圭一君
Uh, didn't you hear
a strange sound just now?
いや
今 変な音が聞こえなかったか？
（ﾚﾅ）本当に？
Really?
Yeah. I'm sure.
（圭一）ああ 聞き間違いじゃない
Then you go see.
じゃ 圭一君 見てきて
ああ 分かった
Okay.
レナを怒らせちゃ…
I don't want you to get me mad.
イヤだよ
Trust me.
信用しろ
あっ！ 何だ？ これ
What's this?
あっ 見つけた！
I found it.
（ﾚﾅ）どうして圭一君は
目覚まし時計なんか―
I wonder why you
have an alarm clock.
持ってるのかな？ かな？
I wonder.
レナ！
Rena!
（ﾚﾅ）圭一君のこと信じてたのに…
I did trust you.
You suck, Keiichi-kun!
ひどいよ 圭一君！
（圭一）ンンッ…
- Okay.
- Keiichi-san!
よっしゃ！
（沙都子）圭一さん！
I found where the timed device is!
時限装置の在りか
分かりましたわ！
（梨花）圭一
早く 沙都子のもとへ行くのです！
Keiichi, hurry and
go where Satoko is.
梨花ちゃん！
Rika-chan...
Keiichi, this isn't the first time.
圭一 これは初めてではないのです
アア…
（梨花）前のとき―
If I had showed a bit
more effort last time, then...
ボクに
あと僅かの頑張りがあれば…
ンンッ…
（梨花）だから 今度こそ！
So definitely this time...
（沙都子）圭一さん もう時間が！
（圭一）ンンッ…
Keiichi-san! There's no time left!
（圭一）すまん 梨花ちゃん！
Sorry, Rika-chan!
アハハハッ！
梨花ちゃんは殺されちゃうよ
You're going to get killed.
By Rena,
who's absolutely furious.
（ﾚﾅ）怒ったレナに
きっと殺されちゃうよ
遊んであげるわ おいで
I'll play with you.
Come, cleaver girl.
（梨花）ナタ女…
What do you mean?
（圭一）どういうことだ？
（沙都子）今日の朝のこと―
It's about this morning.
思い出せば 簡単でしたの　ほら…
It was easy when I recalled it.
See.
（生徒１）なんか くさくない？
（生徒２）外からかな？
Doesn't it smell bad?
Is it from outside?
Huh? My ball is missing.
（生徒３）あれ？ ボールがない
Hojo!
You hid it again, didn't you?
（生徒３）
北条(ほうじょう) また お前が隠したんだろう！
That was the smell of gasoline!
あのにおいは
ガソリンだったのですわ
And the ball?
ボールは？
She closed up the rain
gutter's outlet with the ball...
（沙都子）レナさんは
雨どいの出口をボールで詰めて―
２階の屋根の上から―
...and poured it full of gasoline
from the second floor roof!
雨どい いっぱいに
ガソリンを注いだんですの
Then the timed
explosive device is...
じゃ つまり 時限発火装置は…
多分 屋根の上ですわ
（圭一）偉い 沙都子！
Most likely on the roof.
Nice, Satoko!
みんなを頼むぞ
（沙都子）あっ 圭一さん！
I'm leaving everyone to you.
Keiichi-san! Take this!
（沙都子）これを！
（圭一）あっ…
Satoshi
すまん！
Thanks!
Nii-nii...
Can you hear me, Oishi-san?
聞こえるか？ 大石さん
ライターは奪った
I got the lighter!
The timed explosive
device is on the roof.
時限発火装置は屋根の上！
In the rain gutter!
雨どいの中だ！
雨どい…
（熊谷）もう３分 切ってます
The rain gutter?
Less than three minutes!
Maebara-san!
（大石）前原さん！
前原さん！
Maebara-san!
ンンッ！
（大石）前原さん 急いで！
Maebara-san! Hurry!
Less than one minute!
残り１分 切りました！
（大石）アア…
あっ あれだ！ ンンッ！
There it is!
Cancel
間に合った… 間に合ったー！
I made it in time.
I made it in time!
Great! Charge in!
（大石）よし 全員 突入！
人質の保護と犯人の確保！
Save the hostages
and capture the suspect!
大石さん！ 消防からッス！
Oishi-san!
It's from the fire department!
（熊谷）現場は依然
気化したガソリンにより―
The scene is in great danger
due to the vaporized gasoline!
危険度は最大！
突入班の即時退却を進言しています
They're suggesting the team
that charged in retreats.
なに？
（熊谷）発火装置がなくても―
What?
The explosive device isn't there,
but it's extremely dangerous.
危険度は最大級の現場だそうです
（大石）ンンッ…
（大石）
まだ 前原さんが残っている！
Maebara-san is still there.
（圭一）あっ レナ
Rena!
I can't believe you were
able to find out it was here.
まさか こんな所に隠したの
見つけるとはね
これで全て失敗か…
（圭一）ゲームセットだな レナ
I guess it's all over now.
Game set, Rena.
宇宙人と必死に戦ってたのに…
I was doing my
best to fight the aliens.
If humankind perishes,
it's going to be all your fault.
これで人類が滅んじゃったら
圭一君のせいだからね
はぁ？ 宇宙人？
Aliens?
そんなの 今どき
誰が信じるかってえの
Who in the world
believes in aliens nowadays?
Stupid.
バ～カ！
（ﾚﾅ）ンンッ…
（圭一）
どうしても信じさせたいなら―
If you really
want me to believe it...
俺たち部活メンバーには
簡単な方法があるじゃねえかよ
...there's a simple way
club members settle things.
You're saying
whoever wins is right?
（ﾚﾅ）
勝ったほうが正義ってことだね？
That's right.
そういうことさ
俺に負けたら
そんときは覚悟してもらうぜ
If you lose,
then you'd better watch out.
私に勝ったら
どうするっていうの？
If you win,
what are you going to do?
（圭一）
もちろん俺専属のメイドさんだよな
Naturally, get my very own maid.
It's going to begin with
a "good morning" in the morning...
朝は“おはようございます”から
夜は“おやすみなさい”まで
...and end with
a "good night" at night.
たっぷり ご奉仕三昧だぜ！
It's going to be filled
with personal services.
アハハハッ！ 圭一君らしいな
That's like you.
Maebara-san! Jump!
前原さん 飛び降りて！
It's not working.
ダメっすね
大石さん！
（大石）うん？
Oishi-san!
Yeah...
（岡村(おかむら)）あっ 前原さん しっかり！
Maebara-san, keep it up!
（富田(とみた)）危ない！ 後ろ後ろ！
（生徒たち）頑張れ！
Watch out! Behind! Behind!
（隊員）ちょっと！
（沙都子）あっ！
Hey!
（魅音）梨花ちゃん！
Rika-chan!
（圭一）あのときさ…
During the one-on-one with
water guns, didn't you think it?
水鉄砲で一騎打ちしたとき
思わなかったか？
“もう１回
こんな戦いをしてみたい”って
That you wanted to have
this kind of fight again?
（ﾚﾅ）ええ 思ってた！
Yeah, I thought that.
ヘヘッ…
この緊張感 たまらねえぜ
I can't get enough of this tension.
決着がつくことすら
興ざめするくらいにな！
I get shivers just
thinking it's gonna end.
アハハハッ！
負けても恨まないでね
Don't blame me if you lose!
（生徒たち）頑張れ 頑張れ！
（生徒）負けるな 前原さん！
He might...
（梨花）彼なら… 圭一なら―
Keiichi might...
出口なき惨劇の迷路を
打ち破れるかもしれない
...be able to find an exit
out of this tragic maze.
So I'm gonna ask one more time.
（圭一）
んじゃ もう１回 確認するぜ
俺が勝ったら―
If I win, then it's going to be
days full of personal service.
俺専属のメイドになって
ご奉仕三昧の毎日だ
人前では “これが
私のご主人さまです”って―
You're going to introduce me as
your master in front of everyone.
ちゃんと紹介するんだぞ
かわいい服じゃないとイヤだよ
（圭一）そこは任せろ！
It has to be a cute outfit.
Leave that up to me.
The director will direct
the various things you'll wear.
監督の完全監修のもと
いろいろと取りそろえてやるぜ
Great! Great!
すごい すごい！
I don't plan to lose,
but it sounds like so much fun.
負ける気なんて さらさらないけど
なんだか楽しそう！
Next is about if you win.
（圭一）次はレナが勝った番だ
レナが勝ったら
俺は レナの話を信じる
If you win,
then I'll believe your story.
I'll believe that aliens
control the world.
世界は 宇宙人に
支配されてるって話を信じてやる
Even if you claw
at your throat and die...
お前が
喉をかきむしって死んでも―
最期は ちゃんと看取(みと)ってやるから
安心しろ
...I'll be by your side,
so don't worry.
（ﾚﾅ）なんだか
私が勝っても つまんないね
It's not fun if I win.
（圭一）何だよ？ 変えるのか？
What?
Are you gonna change it?
私も 圭一君と同じご褒美がいいな
I want the same reward as yours.
I'm gonna be the maid?
（圭一）俺がメイドかよ？
You don't have to be a maid.
別に メイドじゃなくていいよ
（ﾚﾅ）でも ほかは同じ
（圭一）あっ…
But the rest is the same.
（ﾚﾅ）
朝は 私に“おはよう”って言って
I want you to say "good
morning" to me in the morning...
...and "good night" to me at night.
夜は
私に“おやすみ”って言ってほしい
I want you to be
really nice to me...
いっぱい 私に優しくして
いっぱい 私を楽しくさせてほしい
...and to make things for me.
あれ？ これじゃ 私が勝っても
圭一君が勝っても―
Oh...
Then whether you or I win,
we'll always be together.
私たち ずっと一緒なんだね…
We'll be together,
but the treatment will be different.
一緒ではあるが
待遇に違いがある！
アハハッ…
I'll say it first!
先に言っとく！
（ﾚﾅ）なに？
What?
It was fun.
楽しかったぜ！
私もだよ
For me too.
（圭一）チッ… やるな
Damn. You're good.
もう決着ついたんだよね？
The fight's over now, right?
まだ ついてねえ
Not yet.
そいつを振り下ろすまでは
まだ つかないぜ
Until you swing
that down, it isn't over.
I don't want to.
イヤだ…
（圭一）えっ？
I don't want to.
イヤだよ… イヤだ
（泣き声）
I don't want to...
Why did it end up like this?
（ﾚﾅ）どうして こんなことに
なっちゃったんだろう…
Where did it become weird?
どこで変になっちゃったんだろう…
I thought I believed in everybody.
私は
みんなを信じてたはずなのに…
When couldn't I believe in you?
どこで 信じられなく
なっちゃったんだろう？
どうして 大好きな仲間たちに
こんな恐ろしいことを…
Why am I doing this
to the people I love?
お… お前
気づいたのか？ 気づけたのかよ？
Did you realize?
Were you able to realize?
（泣き声）
どうして私は―
Why did I wreck all
those days that were fun?
あんなにも楽しかった日々を
自分で壊してしまったんだろう？
（圭一）お前 やっぱり すげえよ！
You're really amazing!
You were able
to realize your mistake!
（圭一）お前は
自分自身の間違いに気づけたんだよ
さすがだ… さすがだよ レナ！
You're awesome!
You're awesome, Rena!
I hurt my friends.
（ﾚﾅ）仲間を傷つけたよ…
魅ぃちゃんに ひどいことしたよ
（圭一）あとで謝っとけ
I did terrible things to Mi-chan.
Apologize to her later.
俺的には 当分の間
姉妹の入れ替わりを見抜けて―
I think it's a good scar for me
to tell the sisters apart with.
ちょうどいい傷痕だと思ってるぞ
（圭一）簡単なことだったんだ
It was simple.
You would've done something
that everyone can easily do.
誰でも思いつく―
とても簡単なことを
すればよかったんだ！
If something was wrong,
if you were suspicious...
何かヤバかったり
疑いそうになったり―
...or if something painful
happens, then you consult...
つらいことが あったときはな
仲間に… 仲間に相談するんだよ
You consult your friends.
そうだよね…
That's right.
That's right!
そうだよね
（泣き声）
Yes.
（梨花）そう…
それこそが とても簡単で―
That was
something very simple...
...and an ultimate key
that was very close.
とても身近な所にある
万能の鍵だった
お互いを許し合い
約束し合うことで―
Forgiving each other,
and promising each other...
疑心暗鬼に打ち勝ち―
...should've been the magic key
to go against the doubts...
全ての惨劇を解決できる―
...and solve the mystery.
魔法の鍵のはずだった
However, there are still
mysteries left in Hinamizawa...
だが その鍵だけでは
開けられない謎が―
まだ この雛見沢には残っている
...that cannot be
opened with only that key.
（圭一）ウウッ… やるな 沙都子！
You're good, Satoko.
おーほっほっほっ！
You're a hundred thousand years
too early to win against me.
私に勝とうなんて―
10万年早いですわよ
（圭一）ンンッ！
If Satoko is serious,
then I need to be serious too.
沙都子が本気なら ボクも
本気を出さないといけませんです
All right
I'm gonna be serious too!
よ～し レナも本気でいくからね！
よしよし 盛り上がってきたね
Good, good! It's getting heated!
Sorry to bother you
when you're having fun...
楽しそうなところ―
ジャマして
ごめんなさい
...but there's
a visitor for Furude-san.
古手(ふるで)さんに
お客さまが来ていますよ
（大石）綿流しの夜…
On Cotton Drifting night,
Tomitake-san and Takano-san died.
富竹(とみたけ)さんと鷹野(たかの)さん
お亡くなりになったんですよ
Yes. That's how it is.
（梨花）そう… そういうこと…
いいわ 遊んであげる
Fine.
I'll play with it
during this endless June.
永遠に終わらない この６月を…
好きなだけね
As much as I want.
When They Cry